Guide to the Archives of Irish America Collection on the Emerald Societies of New York AIA.057
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Archives of Irish America Collection on the Emerald Societies of New York
1977-2004
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Archives of Irish America
AIA.057
1 Linear Feet in 1 record carton
The collection contains primarily printed materials such as circular letters, dinner journals and flyers related to the activities of Emerald Societies in New York City.
Related Material at the Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Missing Title
County Societies, AIA 003
United Irish Counties Association, AIA 056
Scope and Content Note
The collection consists of programs, announcements and dinner-dance journals from social events of the Emerald Societies in the New York metropolitan area. Also of note is a photograph of the NYPD Emerald Society marching in the St. Patrick's Day Parade down 5th Avenue (Box 1, folder 18A).
Access Restrictions
Open for research without restrictions.
Custodial History
Materials were collected from inviduals and staff of the Archives.
Arrangement
Files organized alphabetically by section of society.
Historical/Biographical Note
Emerald Societies are fraternal and family organizations whose members are of Irish American ancestry. The societies exist to promote and foster an appreciation and cultivation of the heritage and culture of the Irish American community as well as provide a common meeting place for activities and events, often charitable in nature. Societies are often found within organizations, as this collection illustrates, including the Fire Department, Departments of Police and Correctional Officers, and the Board of Education, among others. Emerald Societies exist all over the United States. This collection represents a portion of the societies in New York City and State.
Irish Americans -- Social life and customs.; Irish Americans -- Societies, etc.
- Consolidated Edison Emerald Society 30th Annual Dinner Dance, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Emerald Society Board of Education, City of New York Annual Dinner Dance, 1986, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Emerald Society Board of Education, City of New York Annual Dinner Dance, 1991-1996 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Emerald Society Department of Correction Annual Dinner Dance, 1995-1996 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Emerald Society Department of Correction Annual Dinner Dance, 1997-1999 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Emerald Society Fire Department City of New York Silver Jubilee 1956-1981 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Emerald Golf Society of Greater New York, 1982-1984 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Emerald Golf Society of Greater New York, 1986-1989 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Emerald Golf Society of Greater New York 17th Annual Banquet, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Emerald Golf Society of Greater New York 21st Annual Banquet, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Grand Council of United Emerald Societies Annual Dinner Dance, 1977, 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Grand Council of United Emerald Societies Annual Dinner Dance, 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Grand Council of United Emerald Societies Annual Dinner Dance, 1986-1988 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Grand Council of United Emerald Societies Annual Dinner Dance, 1993-1995 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Grand Council of United Emerald Societies 21st Annual Dinner Dance, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Manhattan and Bronx Surface Transit Operation Authority Emerald Society Annual Dinner Dance, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Manhattan and Bronx Surface Transit Operation Authority Emerald Society Annual Dinner Dance, 1978, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Emerald Society Inc. New York City Transit Authority Annual Dinner Dance, 1982-1983, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Emerald Society New York State Courts Annual Dinner Dance, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Emerald Society New York Police Department (NYPD): St. Patrick's Day Parade (photograph), undated (Box 1, Folder 18A)
- Emerald Society Telephone and Communications Worker Annual Dinner Dance, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Emerald Society Triborough Bridge and Tunnel Authority, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 21)